我们,是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文!
and Steven!
历史的冲突
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
presisco
翻译
零玖/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
史蒂文!
Steven.
杰米!
Jamie.
安全滑垒
Safe.
这挺有趣的
We have fun.
那么,你有什么东西吗?
So, you got the goods?
不,我有更"东西"的东西(Goods-货物,Gooder-更好的)
Oh, I've got gooder than the goods.
Bum-da-da-dum-dum dum-da!
喔?一场戏!
Wha--? A play!
我今晚主持试镜
I'm holding auditions tonight.
这是个本地制作
It's a local production
漂流宇宙,搜寻星辰
drifting through space, looking for stars.
如果您在寻澡好演盐,
If you need a great actor,
那您可早对银了
you come to the right guy.
你是怎么了?
What was that?
一种口音而已
An accent?
我不知道是哪种
I don't know.
演戏!
Acting
杰米,杰米,杰米
Jamie, Jamie, Jamie.
其他人呢?
Where's everyone else?
呃,只有你来了
Uh, you're the only one that showed up.
但是,嘿,有的戏只有一个演员,
But, hey, some plays only have one person in them,
所以我们的阵容可大了一倍哦
so we're already in 200% better shape than that.
你数学是体育老师教的吧...
That sounds like some strange math...
但我准备好了
But I'm ready.
好极了
Great.
这是一份剧本
Here's a copy of the script.
"沙滩小镇或铩羽而归-威廉·杜威传"
"Beach City or bust: The tale of William Dewey."
这是我的第一部作品,所以必须要激动人心
This is my first production, so it needs to be exciting.
要成为经典
It needs to be classic.
要得到杜威市长的所有支持
It needs to be fully funded by mayor Dewey.
这个倒的确是...
And it is...
因为剧本是他写的
Because he wrote it.
这个讲的是什么?
What's it about?
我很高兴你问了这个问题
I'm glad you asked.
这个故事讲的是沙滩镇是如何
This is the story of how Beach City
在200年前建立的,
was founded nearly 200 years ago
而这源于我的曾-曾-曾-曾祖父
by my great-great-great-great grandfather,
威廉·杜威
William Dewey.
这是非常重要的历史传记
It's a truly important historical tale
对我来讲有非常重要的情感与政治意义
with a lot of sentimental and political importance to me.
那么,我们刚要开始准备
Well, we're just about to get started.
呃,您愿意看看我们的彩排吗,市长?
Uh, would you like to sit in on the rehearsal, mayor?
不要在意我的存在,实在抱歉
Don't mind if I do. Oh, pardon me.
好吧,史蒂文
Okay, Steven.
既然你是唯一一个来这里的人,
Since you're the only one who showed up,
由你来出演主角威廉·杜威
you'll be playing the lead role of William Dewey.
搞定试镜了!
Nailed the audition.
然后其他的角色嘛,我猜我得演...
And for the other roles, I guess I'll have to play...
所有人
All of them.
船漂泊在海上,
The ship is out at sea.
烈日炙烤着站在甲板上的船员们
The sun beats down on the crew while they stand on deck.
突然间,高挑,硬朗般英俊的男子
Suddenly, the tall, ruggedly handsome man
\站在船员面前开始讲话...Nstanding in front of them speaks...
"船员们,我很高兴你们愿意与我成为远征的一员,"
"Crew, I'm so glad you could be part of this journey with me
"寻找新大陆,"
as we search for a new land
"并建立一座新的城邦"
to build a distinguished new city in.
"哦,威廉·杜威船长,你是如此出色的一名船长啊,"
"Oh, captain William Dewey, you're such a good captain.
"我们从没经历过如此顺利的远航"
Never has a voyage been so super good."
"说的不错,巴迪大副"
"Good point, first mate buddy."
嗨皮一下
For fun.
哦,不
Oh, no.
那是正在接近的风暴吗?
Is that a wild squall approaching us?
显然这可不好啊
Surely this can't be good.
冷静一下,我的船员们
"Be calm, my crew."
我可以轻易解决困境,用我的
I'll just save us with my
史诗级,超自然的力量!
heroic, supernatural ability."
然后威廉·杜威变成了一个15米高的巨人
And then William Dewey grows into a 50-foot giant
并将船安全的携带到海岸边
and carries the boat safely to shore.
船员们认为他是如此优秀的船长,
The crew thinks he's so good at being captain
决定选他当沙滩市的第一任市长
that they elected him to be the first mayor of Beach City.
剧终
The end.
哇,杜威市长,这个剧本太棒了!
Wow, mayor Dewey. That was really good.
那当然
Yeah.
威廉·杜威其实是个...
William Dewey is a really,
"好",人物
good character...
但也许我们能发掘出威廉·杜威的另一面?
But maybe we could bring out another side of William Dewey?
他内心的,挣扎?
See his struggles?
伟大的威廉·杜威从不,犹豫!
The great William Dewey didn't struggle.
他做任何事都是一次成功-
He was good at everything on the first try --
就像我写的剧本
just like me when I wrote this play.
不用改任何一个字
Not a single word needs to be changed.
但,也许-
But maybe --
不要忘了是谁出的钱
Don't forget who's funding this.
那么,彩排的不错,先生们
Well, nice hustle, gentlemen.
坚持下去
Keep it up.
遵命
Aye, aye.
这会是场灾难
This is gonna be a disaster.
什么?
What?
这是个非常辣鸡的故事
It's a terrible story.
威廉·杜威太假了
William Dewey is totally unbelievable.
因为他能变到15米高?
'Cause he grows 50 feet?
不,他没有个性
No, he's got no character.
但剧本一直在说他有多好啊
But the script kept saying he was really good.
正是如此
Exactly.
人怎么可能没有缺陷?
How can a guy have no faults?
人必须有缺陷
To be human is to be flawed.
真正的英雄一定有内心斗争
A real hero must struggle.
说的,太好了!
That's so beautiful.
并且,完全没有体现在
And, also, totally not represented
杜威市长的剧本中
in mayor Dewey's script.
我的第一部戏-很可能也是最后一部
My first play -- and probably my last.
嘿,珍珠
Hey, Pearl.
珍珠?
Pearl?
史蒂文,你回来啦
Steven, you're back.
是啊
Yeah.
演艺圈真是不好混啊
Show business is rough.
有什么我可以帮忙的吗?
Is there something I can help you with?
除非你能让威廉·杜威变得有趣
Not unless you can make William Dewey interesting.
你怎么知道的威廉·杜威?
How do you know William Dewey?
我要在这部戏中出演他
I'm gonna be him in this play.
但他非常无趣
But he's totally boring.
他很完美,而且从不犯错
He's perfect, and he never makes mistakes.
真希望我也能这么评价自己啊
Wish I could say the same for myself.
是啊,但没人是那样
Yeah, but nobody's like that.
每个人都可能出错,
Everybody gets stuff wrong.
之后再不断努力--这并不容易
And then you have to keep going, and it's hard,
而这也是为什么坚持如此重要
which is why it's great when you never stop trying.
你什么时候变得这么睿智了?
When did you get so smart?
嗯...这不只是无聊
Hmm. This isn't just boring.
而且非常失实
It's historically inaccurate.
谁写的?
Who wrote this?
杜威市长
Mayor Dewey.
他当时又不在那里
He wasn't even there.
但我在
But I was.
你当时在场?
You were there?
那么,到底发生了什么?
Wait, what really happened?
首先,
Well, for starters,
\"硬朗般英俊"听起来太客气了
"ruggedly handsome" seems rather generous.
史蒂文...
Steven...
这太真实了!
This is so real.
这看起来像是亲身经历过的人写的!
It's like it was written by someone who lived it.
就是这样!
It was.
我不知道你能否看出来,
And I don't know if you can tell,
但,段子是我写的!
but I wrote the jokes.
我当然看得出来
I can tell.
这真是太勇敢,太热烈,太...
It's so gritty, so passionate, so...
尊重史实?
Historically accurate?
还有反转?
And the drama?
这才是我们该演的剧本
This is the play we should be doing.
那开始吧
Let's do it then.
咱们演这个版本吧
Let's put on this version of the play.
但该怎么办?
But how?
我们需要新的服装,新的道具-
We'd need new costumes, new props --
我们没有时间了
we have no time.
而且杜威市长会搞死我们的
And mayor Dewey will have our heads.
但杰米,你自己说过-
But Jamie, you said it yourself --
真正的英雄会有内心斗争
"a real hero struggles."
天哪,你说的没错!
Ah, jiminy, you're right.
这部戏明天晚上表演时
This show will go on tomorrow night
由你出演威廉·杜威
with you as captain William Dewey
而我则表演剩下的角色
and I as the remaining roles.
剩下的所有吗?
All of them?
所有!
All of them.
Sh...boom, ahh,
表演
acting.
我能,做你旁边吗?
Mind if I have a seat?
可-以吧
Okay...
哦,你造吗,我写的剧本呦
Oh, you know, I wrote this play.
我希望杜威市长不要对改动太过生气
I hope mayor Dewey isn't mad about the changes
走一步看一步吧
guess we'll have to see.
你紧张吗?
Are you nervous?
当然
Of course.
这对我的生涯至关重要
This could either make or break my career.
你可能失去邮局的工作?
You could lose your job at the post office?
这事关我的个人爱好啊
This could either make or break my hobby.
演戏
Acting.
木板先生和木板小姐们,
Boardies and gentleboardies,
今晚,我非常高兴能像你们奉上...
tonight, I am thrilled to present to you...
威廉·杜威传
"The tale of William Dewey."
耶!沙滩镇最叼!
Yeah -- Beach City rules.
嘘～
Shh.
哦,船长啊,我的船长,
Oh, captain, my captain,
“O Captain! My Captain!”致敬沃尔特·惠特曼的同名诗歌与“死亡诗社”
还有多久我们远航舰船的柔软舰首
how long until the soft lips of our sailing ship
亲上新大陆那粗糙的胡茬?
kiss the rugged beard of new lands?
我知道我们已经航行了好几个月了,
I know we've been journeying for many months,
但肯定我们会遇到什么的
but surely we'll run into something soon.
大海肯定没那么宽广吧?
The ocean can't be that big.
他在那,嗨,史蒂文
There he is. Hi, Steven.
你是如此的有才啊
You're so talented.
在我的老家我被称作"蠢蛋杜威"
Back home they called me "Dewey the dunce,"
此处可猜测威廉·杜威是以哥伦布为原型的——二者都来自于欧洲，都被家乡人蔑视，
都发现了有原住民的大陆（水晶战士）
人们说我发现不了陆地,即使我就站在上面
said I couldn't find land even if I was standing on it.
搞毛...
What the...
现在我开始害怕他们说的是对的
And I'm starting to fear that they were right.
那在船左侧突然出现的光是什么?
What light through yon stage left breaks?
哦,又发生了什么?
Oh, what now?
这是东面,而且我们是水晶战士
It is the east, and we are The Crystal Gems.
此处台词致敬莎士比亚的“罗密欧与朱丽叶”的原句——
"But soft! What light through yonder window breaks? It is the east, and Juliet is the sun"
蛤?这不在剧本中啊
What? This wasn't in the script.
这也不包含在预算中
This wasn't in the budget, either.
你好,我是珍珠
Greetings. I am Pearl.
而且我来
And I come to you
是以信使的身份代表伟大的,
as a messenger of the brilliant,
罗丝·石英!
Rose Quartz.
我们要求你掉转船头
We ask that you turn your ship around.
你们前往的土地
The land you are headed for
对于你们人类太过危险
is no walk in the park for your species.
胡扯
Nonsense.
我才不会听你们这种人的话
I won't take orders from the likes of you.
好吧,那么...
Well, then...
你必须回头,否则就会被跳船
You should turn around lest you fall into the sea.
你也知道,
And you know,
人类不怎么会游泳
humans aren't very good swimmers.
他们不会
They ain't.
看来我只能回家了
I'll just return home
如同一个失败的蠢蛋
like the failure dunce I am.
呃,我甚至都不能搞定船帆
Ugh. I can't even turn a sail right.
为什么我总是遭受挫折?
Why must I always struggle?
喔,老爸,那真是个屌丝
Wow, dad, what a loser.
哦,船长,我的船长
Oh, captain, my captain,
我们已经从路线漂流出了好几英里了
we've drifted Miles from our course.
这些波涛我之前可没见过
These waves are nothing like I've ever seen before.
胡扯!这只是毛毛雨而已
Nonsense. This is only a drizzle.
好吧,也许是场夏天的雷阵雨
Okay, maybe a light summer storm.
左舷那边是什么?
What's that portside?
操作杆
Lever.
噢
Oh.
船长,它抓住我了
Captain, it's got me.
巴迪大副!
First mate buddy.
不论如何,千万不要放弃你的搜寻
Whatever you do, don't give up your search.
你是我认识的最勇敢的人,因为你坚持尝试,
You're the bravest man I know, because you try,
即使你已经失败了无数次
even though you fail so, so much.
巴迪,不～!
Buddy, noooo!
哦,巴迪,你死的好冤啊～
Oh, buddy, a stale biscuit to the end.
而现在我的船将沉入深渊
And now my boat will sink into the depths.
多灾多难的蠢蛋杜威
Dewey the disastrous dunce.
这是什么?
What's this?
我的凤尾鱼啊!四重掐头掌!
Holy anchovies. The quadruple noogie.
一个只存在于传说中的招式
A move that's only been spoken of in legends.
啊!它朝这里来了!
Ah. It heads this way.
哦,求求你,掐头神,不要伤害我
Oh, please, goddess of noogies, don't hurt me.
喔,我成功了!
Whoa. I've made it!
陆地!甜美的,坚实的陆地!
Land! Sweet, solid land!
谢谢你,女巨人
Thank you, giant woman.
你也许不想要呆在这里,这块土地非常危险
You may not want to stay, this land is dangerous.
不,我会留下
No, I will stay.
因为我是威廉·杜威,
For I am William Dewey,
而我并不会因失败而放弃
and I don't give up in the face of failure.
而这也让我变得如此伟大
That's what makes me great.
好吧
Very well then.
但我不保证我不会再次插手的
But I can't promise you I won't interfere again.
我应该用这块新陆地的名字
I shall name this new land
纪念我死去的大副,巴迪
in honor of my dead first mate, buddy.
我还活着!
I'm alive.
好吧,就叫沙滩市吧
Okay, Beach City it is.
选杜威
当市长
什么?
What?
很高兴知道曾祖父是个有缺陷的活生生的人物
Nice to know great grandpa was a real person with flaws.
很大胆啊,老爸
Gutsy move dad.
杜威市长!
Mayor Dewey!
市长-
Mayor --
这个给你,这个给你...
one for you, and one for you...
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我能跟天才交谈一下吗
If I could have a moment with the talent.
哦～哦
Oh.
杰米-
Jamie.
哦,耶!
Oh, yeah.
做的太棒了
Fantastic work.
我喜欢那条信息-"请投给杜威市长"
I loved the message. "Vote mayor Dewey."
要不我再给你安排个位置-
How about I offer you another role --
沙滩市社区剧院的首席导演
lead director of Beach City community theater.
你能制作更多的戏剧-
You could put on more plays --
只要预算允许的话
as long as the budget allows it.
呃,谢谢,先生
Uh, thank you, sir.
许多功劳属于珍珠
A lot of the credit should go to Pearl.
你可以说她是"内部情报源"
You could say she was an "inside source."
我是个多才多艺的宝石人
I am a gem of many talents --
专注事实是我的能力之一
a dedication to fact is just one of them.
谢谢你保存了我的家族传奇
Thank you for preserving my legacy.
朋友间200年算什么?
Oh, what's 200 years between friends.
那么...
Well...
我得走了
I must be off then
得去享受选民们的称赞了
to bask in the adulation of my constituents.
你知道吗,我不记得有个竞选标语
You know, I don't remember there being a campaign slogan
在故事的结尾
at the end of that story.
艺术并不总是遵循逻辑的,珍珠
Art doesn't always need a reason, Pearl.
有的时候只在于让观众高兴
Sometimes it's just gotta make the audience happy.
这就是为什么总要以段子结尾
That's why you always end on a joke.
你
♪ You
爱,如你
♪ love like you